Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to introduce the concept of procurement.
Now, procurement management then.
I mean procurement, as the name suggests,
what does it mean?
It means buying from outside, going from
outside.
It's getting goods and services from
outside of the organisation.
Equipment, supplies, labour, raw
materials, anything that we need that we
don't have in-house, then we have to
outsource it.
We have to go outside of the organisation.
Right, so we're purchasing raw materials.
materials, we don't have
the raw materials ourselves,
we're purchasing it from a
vendor or equipment, labour.
We can't do the work
ourselves, so we're going outside
getting contractors and
consultants and so on and so forth.
So that is what procurement
relates to, getting
goods and services from
outside of the organisation.
All right.
Now, as a general rule, generally,
whatever the reason is for going outside,
right, there's many, many
reasons, why we would
want to outsource the work
versus doing it in-house.
Many reasons, and
we're going to cover those
reasons in another
video, in a separate video.
But whatever the reason is, collectively
it is known as a make-or-buy analysis.
So we are determining should we do it
in-house or should we outsource the work.
And that is known as a make-or-buy
analysis.
So it could be because it's cheaper to do.
It's cheaper.
You know, we may do
a cost-benefit, analysis
or there may be some other reason as well.
It is not known as a cost-benefit
analysis.
It is known as a make
or buy analysis, whatever
the reason is for outsourcing the work.
Now as a general rule also, any questions
is generally, so any PMP exam questions on
procurement is generally going to be from
the buyer's perspective.
So in other words, if the question doesn't
state or doesn't imply whether you are the
buyer or the seller, then you are the
buyer.
So most of the procurement management
section is from the buyer's perspective.
And most of the questions, if it doesn't
tell you if you're the buyer or the
seller, or there's no hint anywhere in
either the scenario or the question or any
of the option choices, then the assumption
is that you are the buyer.
The seller is offering you goods and
services, And as a buyer, you are
purchasing those goods and services from
the seller.
So in other words, since we are outsourcing
the work now, we are now the customer.
And that's something very important to
understand when it comes to procurement.
We are now the customer.
So all of the discussion that we've had
with all of those other processes and
knowledge areas and all of the other
sections that we've covered, We are the
project team, we are the project manager,
right?
Or the team facilitator, and we are
working for the customer.
With procurement, it's now the other way
around.
We are the customer, right?
So we are now giving our requirements to
the seller.
We are giving our requirements to the
vendor that we have hired.
From those requirements, we are going to
come up with the scope, baseline,
the schedule baseline, the cost baseline.
That's all going to be discussed as part
of the contract.
We're going to cover contracts later on as
well in a separate video.
But the important part is we
are now the customer, we are
the key stakeholder and the
vendor is doing the work for us.
So this is now a project for the vendor.
Okay.
So that's something very important.
So you have to think of it from the other
way around now.
Also, you have to think of it also when If
any of you guys are working for a vendor
organization, if any of you guys are
consultants or contractors, right,
and you work for a vendor organization
and you are working for a customer, right?
You are doing a project for a customer.
Again, remember, you
have to think of it from the
customer's perspective,
not from your perspective.
So procurement is always, we are now with
the customer.
Now, also, there's many different terms
that PMI can use that describe a seller,
for example, vendor, suppliers.
So these are all general
terms that are used in everyday
language, and the PMI will
use all of those general terms.
They could identify them as a seller,
as a vendor, general contractor,
subcontractor, and so and so on and so
forth.